I stand in secret silence
（デス烈子(れつこ)の歌声）
KARAOKE
I scream into the darkness!
But the pain never ends!
（電話の着信音）
（店員）あと10分で
終了時間となります
Your time is up in ten minutes.
Would you like to extend it?
延長いたしますか？
（烈子）あっ 終わりまーす
Ah, I'm done.
（烈子）
このカラオケボックスは 私の聖域
These karaoke rooms are my sanctuary.
A place of tranquility
on my way home from work.
会社帰りの安らぎの場所
We await your next visit.
（店員）またのお越しを
お待ちしております
I can never let anyone see it...
（烈子）絶対に
誰にも見られちゃいけない―
秘密の場所
My secret place.
RAGE
♪～
～♪
（先生のかけ声）
（先生）プロテイン！
Protein!
（アシスタント）はい
今日のヨガ講座は ここまでです
Okay!
That's it for today's yoga class!
プロテイン！
Protein!
また来週も
いい汗かきましょう
Let's work up a good
sweat again next week!
痛(いて)てて…
Oww...
ああ…
（鷲美(わしみ)）筋肉痛？
慣れないうちは結構ハードでしょう
Sore muscles? It's quite hard
if you're not used to it.
ええ まあ…
Yeah, I guess...
I won't put on excess muscle
from training here, will I?
ここで教わってたら 無駄に筋肉
ついちゃったりしませんかね？
（鷲美）どういうこと？
（烈子）だって あの先生―
What do you mean?
Well, that instructor leaves
yoga to his assistant,
ヨガはアシスタントに任せて―
（先生）プロ テイン
プロ テイン…
ずーっと
筋トレばっか やってるし―
（先生）プロ テイン
プロ テイン…
and all he does is muscle building.
プロテインとしか言わないし…
He keeps saying "protein".
何ていうか どう見ても
ヨガの講師とは名ばかりの その…
No matter how you look at it,
he's a yoga instructor in name only.
So...
（ゴリ）筋肉バカって
言いたいのね
"Meat head."
Is that what you want to say?
いえいえ
別に そういうわけじゃ…
No, no! I didn't mean that!
烈子ちゃん あの先生はね―
Retsuko, he may not look it, but...
ああ見えて 本場インドで
厳しい修行を積んだ―
he's an amazing person who went
through strict training in India.
立派な方なのよ
（先生）プロテイ～ン！
Protein!
その証拠に ほら見て
Here's the proof!
私 ここに
通うようになってから―
Since I've been coming here,
my upper arms have become so defined.
すっごく二の腕がスッキリしたの
ほ～ら！
（烈子）うわああ～
Look!
不安にさせないでください！
That's not reassuring!
（鷲美）烈子ちゃんは
何で ヨガ始めたの？
Why do you come to yoga, Retsuko?
えっ あ～ え～っと…
Uh, well... You see...
そりゃ きれいになりたいからに
決まってるわよね？
It's because you want
to be beautiful, right?
あっ はあ… まあ
そんなとこですかね
Yes, well, something like that.
アハ アハハハ…
（烈子）結婚相手 見つけて
会社 辞めるためなんて―
I can't say it's to help me find
a marriage partner so I can quit.
言えないよな…
（鷲美）どうする？
御飯 食べ行く？
What now?
Want to go for dinner?
（ゴリ）あっ いいわね～
この間行った あのお店は？
Sounds nice! How about
that restaurant we've been to before?
キッシュが おいしかったとこ
（鷲美）あそこは もういいな
The one with the yummy quiche.
I'm tired of that place.
Grilled meat, then.
（ゴリ）じゃあ 焼き肉
（鷲美）太るじゃない
I'll get fat.
烈子ちゃんも行くでしょ？
You're coming, right?
Okay? Let's go!
There's so much I want to hear about.
ねっ 行こう
いろいろ 話も聞きたいし
（烈子）あっ すみません
I'm sorry.
帰ります
I'm going home.
冷蔵庫に
片づけなきゃいけない食材―
I have some leftovers
in my fridge that I need to use.
余らしちゃってて
アハ…
あら… そう…
Oh dear... I see...
（先生）フー… プロテイン…
Protein...
（ハイ田(だ)）烈子ってさあ 何か
壁作ってくるとこ あるよなあ
Retsuko... it seems
that she's ignoring us.
Maybe.
（フェネ子(こ)）まあね
She's refused to go out with us
three times already.
３回連続で
飲み会 断られると―
さすがに心 折れるわ ハア～
It's got me down...
その度に
ハイ田の やけ酒に―
Think about how I feel
having to accompany you
つきあわされる
こっちの身にもなってよね
every time you go to drown your sorrows.
何なんだよ 烈子の“用事”って
What's keeping Retsuko so busy?
まさか男とかじゃねえだろうな？
Not some man, right?
多分 違う
Probably not.
それ 烈子に聞いたのか？
Did Retsuko tell you that?
あの子 自分のこと
あんまり話さないでしょ
She doesn't talk a lot about herself.
And I don't ask.
私も聞かないし
ただの憶測ってことか
So, you're just guessing?
推理だよ
An educated guess.
（ハイ田）あ？
Huh?
STARTING MY YOGA CLASS
Who is that?
誰だよ？ これ
（フェネ子）
知らない人が
ヨガ教室で撮った写真
It's a picture that someone
took in their yoga class.
Don't you think the person in
the background looks like Retsuko?
後ろに写ってるの
烈子っぽくない？
どういうことだ？
What are you saying?
烈子って会社を出たら
普通 駅に直行すんの
Retsuko normally goes
straight to the station after work.
でも 週に２回だけ
駅の反対方向に向かうんだよね
But twice a week,
she heads in the opposite direction.
つまり 会社近辺の
どっかに通ってる
She's going somewhere
near the office.
It's twice a week so it's
probably some kind of lesson.
それが週に２回
習い事の可能性大
最近 筋肉痛を訴えてたから
恐らく 体使う系
She's been feeling sore lately,
so it must be something physical.
スポーツジムって
キャラじゃないから―
Since she's not the gym type,
I guessed it was either Pilates or yoga,
ピラティスとかヨガとかかなって
当たりつけて 検索かけたら―
and when I searched,
I found this photo.
その写真がヒット
怖(こえ)えよ お前
敵に回したくねえわ
You're scary.
I wouldn't want to be your enemy.
しょうがないじゃん
烈子が話してくんないんだから
It had to be done.
Retsuko wasn't going to tell us.
（ハイ田）ハア…
（烈子）せっかく誘ってくれたのに
断っちゃった
They were kind to invite me,
but I turned them down.
２人と知り合いになれて
うれしかったけど―
I'm glad that I became
acquaintances with them, but...
やっぱり 会社の人なんだよな
They're people from
the office, after all.
いろいろ聞かれても面倒だし…
It could be awkward
being asked some questions.
はあ～あ…
（ヤギュウの力み声）
（ヤギュウ）駄目だ…
（大上(おおかみ)）あ 俺やるっす
I can't do it.
I'll do it!
ふっ… うお… かってえ
マジ開かねっすよ これ
It's tight! I really can't open it!
坪根(つぼね)の開かずの つくだ煮
"Tsubone's unopenable jars."
まだ開いてなかったのか あれ
So she still hasn't opened it?
（坪根）あら～
My goodness...
烈子さん
ちょうどいいとこに来たわ～
Retsuko, perfect timing.
悪いけど このつくだ煮の瓶
開けてもらってもいい？
Could you open this jar for me?
ものすご～く固いけど
Mind you, it's really tightly sealed.
きっと頑張り屋さんの
あなたなら できるわ…
I'm sure a go-getter
like you would be able to....
きっと頑張り屋さんの
あなたなら できるわ…
（ふたが開く音）
（烈子）あっ 開きました
Ah!
I opened it.
あああ…
（ハイ田）烈子 お前すげえな
Retsuko, you're really something!
えっ 何で？
Huh? Why?
You were like King Arthur back there.
Have you taken up body building?
アーサー王みたいだったぞ
ボディービルでも始めたのか？
（烈子）え～？
What?
おかしいな 確かに
ヨガ教室の写真に写ってたのに
That's strange. It was
definitely a photo from a yoga class.
何の話？
-Is something wrong?
-No, just thinking out loud.
いやいや こっちの話
（烈子）こないだのこと
怒ってるのかな…
Are they angry that
I turned them down the other day?
次 会ったら ちゃんと謝ろう
Next time I see them,
I'll apologize.
やっぱり 烈子ちゃん
私たちのこと 嫌ってるのかしら？
I wonder if Retsuko really
does hate us after all!
（ゴリの泣き声）
（鷲美）
一回 断られただけじゃない
She just declined once!
また今度 誘ってみましょ
Let's try inviting her again next time.
プロテイン…
Protein...
（先生のかけ声）
プロテイ～ン
Protein!
（アシスタント）はい
今日のヨガ講座は ここまでです
That's all for today's yoga class!
Protein!
（先生）プロテイ～ン
（アシスタント）また来週も
いい汗かきましょう！
Let's work up a good
sweat again next week!
（ゴリ）先生
Instructor...
お疲れさまです
Another good class today.
プロテイン…
Protein...
（ゴリ）あっ はい
ありがとうございます
Ah, yes.
Thank you very much.
プロテイ～ン
Protein.
（ゴリ）烈子ちゃ～ん
駅まで一緒に行こ
Retsuko!
Let's go to the station together.
あれっ 今日は
どこも寄らないんですか？
Huh? You're not
stopping anywhere today?
うん 今日は帰るだけ
Right! Today we're just going home!
こないだは すみません
せっかく誘ってくれたのに
I'm sorry about the other day,
turning down your invitation...
That's okay! Water under the bridge.
いいのよ～ そんなこと
ぜ～んぜん気にしてないわよ
（鷲美）
烈子ちゃん 何線で帰るの？
Retsuko, what line do you take?
あっ 田園都市線です
Oh, the Den-en-toshi line.
Which line do you two take?
お二人は どちらに帰るんですか？
（ゴリ）あ～ああ～！
KARAOKE
RECEPTION 2ND FLOOR
ああああああ…
カラオケ 最近 行ってな～い！
I haven't done karaoke in ages!
What?
はっ
（鷲美）私も行ってな～い
Neither have I!
ええっ
What?!
（ゴリ）あら？
鷲美 もしかして―
Washimi, do you feel
like singing, by any chance?
歌いたい気分？
（鷲美）うん…
Yeah...
でも ゴリちゃん 帰るのよね？
But, Gori, we were going home, remember?
どうしよっか～？
中 見てから 決めよっか？
What do you say...
Shall we check it out and decide?
（鷲美）見るだけ見てみよっか～
Let's just take a look.
えっ えっ ちょっと…
Hey! Wait!
いらっしゃいませ お一人様…
Welcome. Party of one...
三名様ですね
A room for three.
I thought you said you were
just going home today?!
今日は帰るって
言ったじゃないですか～
（烈子の泣き声）
It's been too long!
カラオケ久しぶり～
（鷲美）わりと きれいじゃない
This is rather nice.
（ゴリ･鷲美）烈子ちゃん
カラオケって よく来るの？
Do you do karaoke often, Retsuko?
いえ 私は あまり…
No... Not much...
とりあえず何か飲み物 頼もっか
Why don't we order
some drinks for now?
はいっ ビールの人～？
（鷲美）はーい
Who wants a beer?
I do!
（烈子）２人のペースに
巻き込まれないようにしないと
I can't be drawn into their trap.
あ 私 ウーロン茶で
Uh, I'll have Oolong tea.
ビール ビール ウーロン茶ね
了解～！
Two beers and a cup of tea. Copy that!
（店員）フロントです
Front desk.
Two beers and an Oolong cocktail, please.
（ゴリ：小声）ビール２杯と
ウーロンハイ お願いしまーす
（烈子）アルコール混入事件 発生
She's spiking the tea with alcohol!
（鷲美）
そんなに緊張することないのよ
There's no need to be so nervous.
会社の外では 上司も先輩もないわ
同じ女同士でしょ
Outside work, there's no office hierarchy.
We're all women.
そうよ 私たち…
Because we're... yoga buddies!
ヨガダチなんだから
ヨガダチ？
Yoga buddies?
Friends on a journey of self-discovery,
opening chakras,
ヨガを通じて 己を見つめ直し―
チャクラを開いて 宇宙と
一体となることを共に目指す仲間
and becoming one with the universe
together! That's yoga buddies!
それが ヨガダチ
（烈子）いや 私 そんな
大それたこと 考えてませんから
I don't think it's that big a deal!
（ゴリ）心を自由になさい
（エコー）
Free your mind!
Anyway...
（鷲美）とりあえず… 歌おっか
Do you want to sing?
イエーイ！
Yay!
（烈子）ううう…
I wonder what Retsuko's going
to sing for us. I'm really curious.
烈子ちゃん
何歌ってくれるのかな？
超興味ある～！
（鷲美）意外にヒップホップ系とか
Some old-school hip-hop?
アイドル系じゃない？
Or some J-pop?
あっ 私 デス系です
Oh, I'm into death metal.
I can't say that!
（烈子）
なんて言えるわけないじゃん
なんとか
この場を乗り切らないと…
I have to get through this somehow.
（烈子）あっ 私 あんまり
レパートリー ないんですよね
I don't have much of a repertoire.
あっ これ サビしか歌えないな
I only know the chorus of this song.
あ 時間もったいないんで どうぞ
先輩たちから歌ってください
Oh, I'm wasting our time.
You two please sing first.
We have three hours,
take your time and choose.
３時間あるから
ゆっくり選びなさい
（烈子）長期戦に持ち込まれた…
I've been dragged into a long battle!
I've brought your beer
and the Oolong cocktail.
（店員）ビールとウーロンハイ
お持ちしました
（烈子）えーと これも駄目だな
これ 歌詞が中二すぎるしな
I can't do this one...
This one's too teenage...
This is out of my range.
This one is depressing.
これ多分 キーが合わないな これは
ギャラリーが引きそうだしな…
（鷲美）なかなか手ごわいわね
She's a tough one.
Probably the type of girl
who is always on her toes.
多分
壁を作っちゃうタイプの子なのよ
大丈夫 先生は おっしゃったわ
Don't worry.
The instructor told me.
（先生）プロテイ～ン
Protein...
このメモが
私たちを―
This note will guide
us to the right answer.
正しい答えに
導いてくれると
（鷲美）何なの？ その数字
What is that number?
（ゴリ）分からない…
I don't know...
一体 先生は 私たちに
何を伝えようとしているのかしら
I wonder what the instructor
is trying to tell us.
プロテイ～ン
（エコー）
Protein!
はっ
What should I do?
Which one to sing? What do I do?
（烈子）えっと どうしようかな
何歌おうかな…
どうしようかな どうしようかな
（ゴリ）烈子
Retsuko...
That's enough. Give it to me.
もういいわ
貸しなさい
SEND
（デスメタルの音楽）
（烈子）
このカラオケボックスは 私の聖域
These karaoke rooms
are my sanctuary...
REQUEST RECEIVED
私が本当の自分でいられる
秘密の場所
where I can be my true self.
だから 誰にも見られちゃいけない
That's why...
I have to keep it a secret.
ずっと そう信じてきた
That's what I've always believed.
（デス烈子の叫び声）
This is all I ever sing! This is my soul!
All death metal 'cause it makes me whole!
Death!
Metal!
Death metal forever!
（歓声）
（ゴリ）オッ オッ オッ オ～！
（鷲美）あああ～
You'll hurt your throat doing it that way.
そんなやり方じゃ 喉 痛めますよ
もっと しっかり 声帯を閉じて…
Clench your vocal chords, and...
ウアアアアアア！
だから 声帯を閉じるって何よ
Again, how do you
"clench" the vocal chords?!
（鷲美）ぜんっぜん意味分かんない
（烈子）あ～…
I don't understand at all...
（電話の着信音）
（店員）あと10分で終了時間です
Your time is up in ten minutes.
（ゴリ･鷲美）んっ んっ んっ ん…
（烈子）ウフッ
Extend it, please!
延長 お願いしまーす
Subtitle translation: John Haguewood
♪～
～♪